<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Swift on The Tymscar Blog</title><link>/tags/swift/</link><description>Recent content in Swift on The Tymscar Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/swift/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I wrote my Vision Pro killer app (Script Anchor)</title><link>/posts/scriptanchor/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/scriptanchor/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always like VR For 15 years, I&amp;rsquo;ve been captivated by the possibilities of VR/AR. It all became real when I held my first Google Cardboard at Google I/O 2015—here&amp;rsquo;s the moment captured:
My professional and personal life has been deeply intertwined with virtual reality. I spent five fulfilling years harnessing VR&amp;rsquo;s potential at JLR, and for my Bachelor of Science First Class Honours degree at BCU, I pioneered an augmented reality project that allowed users to overlay virtual attractions onto the real world.</description><content>&lt;h1 id="ive-always-like-vr">I&amp;rsquo;ve always like VR&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>For 15 years, I&amp;rsquo;ve been captivated by the possibilities of VR/AR. It all became real when I held my first Google Cardboard at Google I/O 2015—here&amp;rsquo;s the moment captured:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img alt="My Google Cardboard" src="/script-anchor/google-cardboard.jpg">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My professional and personal life has been deeply intertwined with virtual reality. I spent five fulfilling years harnessing VR&amp;rsquo;s potential at JLR, and for my Bachelor of Science First Class Honours degree at BCU, I pioneered an augmented reality project that allowed users to overlay virtual attractions onto the real world. Even outside of work, I&amp;rsquo;ve remained an avid VR enthusiast, frequently engaging with the best headsets out there, from the industry-celebrated Microsoft Hololens to the impressive capabilities of the less known Pimax 8K.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img alt="Selfie with the Hololens" src="/script-anchor/selfie-hololens.jpg">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m sharing this because Script Anchor didn&amp;rsquo;t just appear out of thin air. After nearly a decade immersed in VR and AR, the launch of Apple&amp;rsquo;s Vision Pro left me waiting for that killer app that would speak directly to programmers like myself. That&amp;rsquo;s when I decided to create Script Anchor, potentially &lt;em>the&lt;/em> killer app for the likes of me—tech enthusiasts who code at the cutting edge and value an undisturbed workflow.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="script-anchor">Script Anchor&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Introducing Script Anchor, the spatial computing toolkit for Vision Pro:
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vpUUuARNpEQ?autoplay=0&amp;controls=1&amp;end=0&amp;loop=0&amp;mute=0&amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"
>&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Mac Virtual Display of the Vision Pro is impressive, but its single-screen projection fell short for someone accustomed to a multi-screen setup. For me, flipping back and forth to check a log or send a quick GET request was more than an annoyance—it was a flow-breaker.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img alt="Programming flow" src="https://www.monkeyuser.com/2018/focus/79-focus.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s how Script Anchor addresses this:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>A floating SSH window that&amp;rsquo;s always in view, whether you&amp;rsquo;re coding on a Mac or Linux machine. You can keep an eye on &lt;code>htop&lt;/code>, or swap in any command output—be it logs from a Kotlin Ktor app, Docker, or kernel messages while crafting a Linux driver.
&lt;img alt="Htop running in Script Anchor" src="/script-anchor/htop.png">&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The ability to execute HTTP requests without the need to switch to Postman or cycle through terminal history with &amp;lsquo;↑&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;⏎&amp;rsquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s designed for those times when you&amp;rsquo;re deep in development and any deviation is a distraction.
&lt;img alt="HTTP Requests in Script Anchor" src="/script-anchor/http.png">&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Direct control over Home Assistant lights from the interface—I can&amp;rsquo;t count how many times reaching for my phone to tweak the lighting has disrupted my coding rhythm. With Script Anchor, it&amp;rsquo;s a disruption of the past.
&lt;img alt="Controlling Home Assistant from Script Anchor" src="/script-anchor/home-assistant.png">&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Script Anchor is more labor-intensive than I initially thought, yet the fundamental rule I&amp;rsquo;ve embraced is to launch functional features that can immediately enhance someone&amp;rsquo;s workflow and evolve over time. The ability to add scriptable buttons for quick commands in SSH windows is already on the horizon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can get Script Anchor in the App Store as of &lt;code>TODAY&lt;/code>. For details and links, head over to the dedicated website at &lt;a href="https://scriptanchor.app">https://scriptanchor.app&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See you in the coding zone!&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>