<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nix on The Tymscar Blog</title><link>https://blog.tymscar.com/tags/nix/</link><description>Recent content in Nix on The Tymscar Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 21:39:22 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.tymscar.com/tags/nix/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Public Dotfiles, Private Secrets: My Nix OS Docker Workflow</title><link>https://blog.tymscar.com/posts/nixosdockerwithsecrets/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 21:39:22 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.tymscar.com/posts/nixosdockerwithsecrets/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;For the longest time I ran every container in my homelab on Proxmox. It did the job, but because I use NixOS on my main workstation and NixDarwin on my laptop, I eventually wanted the lab to follow the same declarative model. A few months ago I switched those machines to NixOS as well. Everything went smoothly except for one thing: moving the containers themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem was secrets. I keep my entire configuration, including the lab, in a public &lt;a href="https://github.com/tymscar/dotfiles"&gt;dotfiles repository&lt;/a&gt;. Many of the containers need tokens such as Cloudflare, API keys, you name it, that obviously must not end up on GitHub. Every time I sat down to migrate the stack I put it off for this single reason.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Using Nix to build JS/TS projects with private dependencies</title><link>https://blog.tymscar.com/posts/nixprivatenpmrepos/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 16:50:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.tymscar.com/posts/nixprivatenpmrepos/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://blog.tymscar.com/nix-private-npm-repos/githubActioonsSuccess.png" alt="“Running code from a private repo”)"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nix is a great tool for building software, especially in professional settings because of the guarantees it comes with.&lt;br&gt;
For example, you can be sure that the software you build is reproducible and that it will work on any machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to building packages in the Nix world, you usually end up going with derivation builders already made for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Rust there is &lt;code&gt;rustPlatform.buildRustPackage&lt;/code&gt;, for Go there is &lt;code&gt;go2nix&lt;/code&gt;, for JS/TS there is &lt;code&gt;node2nix&lt;/code&gt;, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Running Jetbrains remote dev servers on NixOS</title><link>https://blog.tymscar.com/posts/jetbrainsremotedevservernixos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:33:45 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.tymscar.com/posts/jetbrainsremotedevservernixos/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://blog.tymscar.com/jb-nix-remote-server/project.png" alt="A remote project"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EDIT: I have raised &lt;a href="https://github.com/NixOS/nixpkgs/pull/243533"&gt;a PR to fix this&lt;/a&gt; upstream and got it merged, so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to follow the guide anymore, you can just use the package on nixpkgs unstable for the time being and later on in the future, a stable branch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past year or so I have been very interested in &lt;a href="https://nixos.org/"&gt;NixOS and Nix&lt;/a&gt; in general.
I have set it up as my &lt;a href="https://github.com/tymscar/dotfiles"&gt;main OS on my desktop&lt;/a&gt;, I have used it on remote VPS instances, and I have used it for local projects as well in the shape of nix environments.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>