<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Debugging on The Tymscar Blog</title><link>https://blog.tymscar.com/tags/debugging/</link><description>Recent content in Debugging on The Tymscar Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.tymscar.com/tags/debugging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>From 400 Mbps to 1.7 Gbps: A WiFi 7 Debugging Journey</title><link>https://blog.tymscar.com/posts/wifi7speedhunt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.tymscar.com/posts/wifi7speedhunt/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I recently upgraded from a &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2019/12/02/the-unifi-dream-machine-router-is-a-great-entry-point-for-networking-nerds"&gt;UniFi Dream Machine&lt;/a&gt; to a &lt;a href="https://techspecs.ui.com/unifi/cloud-gateways/udr7"&gt;UniFi Dream Router 7&lt;/a&gt; because I&amp;rsquo;m getting 2.5 Gbps internet in two weeks and figured I&amp;rsquo;d jump on the WiFi 7 bandwagon while I&amp;rsquo;m at it. My iPhone 17 Pro Max supports it, so why not? After setting everything up, I was getting nowhere near the speeds I expected. Time for some debugging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-disappointing-numbers"&gt;The disappointing numbers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My wired connection was pulling 950 Mbps through a 1 Gbps switch, and iperf3 directly to the UDR7&amp;rsquo;s 2.5 Gbps port showed around 2.3 Gbps. The backbone was solid. But on WiFi 7 (6 GHz, 160 MHz width), standing literally a foot from the router, I was getting around 400 Mbps with iperf3. With 10 concurrent streams it went up to 650 Mbps, but that&amp;rsquo;s still pathetic.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>When Curl Works But IntelliJ Doesn’t: The Ollama Connection Mystery</title><link>https://blog.tymscar.com/posts/intellijollamaconnectionmystery/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.tymscar.com/posts/intellijollamaconnectionmystery/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I run a bunch of internal services through Traefik on my LAN, each with a proper domain name and TLS, so I don’t have to remember ports. One of them is Ollama, sitting on a beefy gaming PC at &lt;code&gt;10.0.0.105&lt;/code&gt; and exposed as &lt;code&gt;https://ollama.tymscar.com&lt;/code&gt;. From the terminal everything behaved exactly as expected: fast responses, certificate valid, models listed. Then IntelliJ IDEA decided this host basically didn’t exist. The “Test Connection” button just said “Failed to connect”. No detail. No hint. Just a smug little red failure.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>