<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Docker on The Tymscar Blog</title><link>/tags/docker/</link><description>Recent content in Docker on The Tymscar Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 21:39:22 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/docker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Public Dotfiles, Private Secrets: My Nix OS Docker Workflow</title><link>/posts/nixosdockerwithsecrets/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 21:39:22 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/nixosdockerwithsecrets/</guid><description>&lt;p>For the longest time I ran every container in my homelab on Proxmox. It did the job, but because I use NixOS on my main workstation and NixDarwin on my laptop, I eventually wanted the lab to follow the same declarative model. A few months ago I switched those machines to NixOS as well. Everything went smoothly except for one thing: moving the containers themselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The problem was secrets. I keep my entire configuration, including the lab, in a public &lt;a href="https://github.com/tymscar/dotfiles">dotfiles repository&lt;/a>. Many of the containers need tokens such as Cloudflare, API keys, you name it, that obviously must not end up on GitHub. Every time I sat down to migrate the stack I put it off for this single reason.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How I deploy private GitHub projects to local self-hosted servers (CI/CD)</title><link>/posts/privategithubcicd/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 18:04:45 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/privategithubcicd/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="how-i-deploy-private-github-projects-to-local-self-hosted-servers-cicd">How I deploy private GitHub projects to local self-hosted servers (CI/CD)&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>I have a lot of experience with massive CI/CD pipelines that deploy private code to public servers. I&amp;rsquo;ve also worked with pipelines that deploy public repositories to private servers, such as my homelab. However, I never experimented with a pipeline that takes a private GitHub repo, builds it, and deploys it to a server on the LAN. That&amp;rsquo;s precisely what I needed for a project I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on that isn&amp;rsquo;t yet public.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>