<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Docker on The Tymscar Blog</title><link>https://blog.tymscar.com/tags/docker/</link><description>Recent content in Docker on The Tymscar Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.tymscar.com/tags/docker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Imgur Geo-Blocked the UK, So I Geo-Unblocked My Entire Network</title><link>https://blog.tymscar.com/posts/imgurukproxy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.tymscar.com/posts/imgurukproxy/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Imgur decided to block UK users. Honestly? I don&amp;rsquo;t really care that much. I haven&amp;rsquo;t actively browsed the site in years. But it used to be everywhere. Back when Reddit embedded everything on Imgur, maybe fifteen years ago, it was genuinely useful. Then Reddit built their own image hosting, Discord did the same, and Imgur slowly faded into the background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except it never fully disappeared. And since the block, I keep stumbling across Imgur links that just show &amp;ldquo;unavailable.&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s mildly infuriating.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Public Dotfiles, Private Secrets: My Nix OS Docker Workflow</title><link>https://blog.tymscar.com/posts/nixosdockerwithsecrets/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 21:39:22 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.tymscar.com/posts/nixosdockerwithsecrets/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;For the longest time I ran every container in my homelab on Proxmox. It did the job, but because I use NixOS on my main workstation and NixDarwin on my laptop, I eventually wanted the lab to follow the same declarative model. A few months ago I switched those machines to NixOS as well. Everything went smoothly except for one thing: moving the containers themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem was secrets. I keep my entire configuration, including the lab, in a public &lt;a href="https://github.com/tymscar/dotfiles"&gt;dotfiles repository&lt;/a&gt;. Many of the containers need tokens such as Cloudflare, API keys, you name it, that obviously must not end up on GitHub. Every time I sat down to migrate the stack I put it off for this single reason.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How I deploy private GitHub projects to local self-hosted servers (CI/CD)</title><link>https://blog.tymscar.com/posts/privategithubcicd/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 18:04:45 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.tymscar.com/posts/privategithubcicd/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="how-i-deploy-private-github-projects-to-local-self-hosted-servers-cicd"&gt;How I deploy private GitHub projects to local self-hosted servers (CI/CD)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a lot of experience with massive CI/CD pipelines that deploy private code to public servers. I&amp;rsquo;ve also worked with pipelines that deploy public repositories to private servers, such as my homelab. However, I never experimented with a pipeline that takes a private GitHub repo, builds it, and deploys it to a server on the LAN. That&amp;rsquo;s precisely what I needed for a project I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on that isn&amp;rsquo;t yet public.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>