<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>MacOS on The Tymscar Blog</title><link>https://blog.tymscar.com/tags/macos/</link><description>Recent content in MacOS on The Tymscar Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.tymscar.com/tags/macos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>When Curl Works But IntelliJ Doesn’t: The Ollama Connection Mystery</title><link>https://blog.tymscar.com/posts/intellijollamaconnectionmystery/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.tymscar.com/posts/intellijollamaconnectionmystery/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I run a bunch of internal services through Traefik on my LAN, each with a proper domain name and TLS, so I don’t have to remember ports. One of them is Ollama, sitting on a beefy gaming PC at &lt;code&gt;10.0.0.105&lt;/code&gt; and exposed as &lt;code&gt;https://ollama.tymscar.com&lt;/code&gt;. From the terminal everything behaved exactly as expected: fast responses, certificate valid, models listed. Then IntelliJ IDEA decided this host basically didn’t exist. The “Test Connection” button just said “Failed to connect”. No detail. No hint. Just a smug little red failure.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How to fix static noise on macOS headphones</title><link>https://blog.tymscar.com/posts/macusbdacstatic/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.tymscar.com/posts/macusbdacstatic/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A bit over a year ago, I bought a pair of &lt;a href="https://steelseries.com/gaming-headsets/arctis-nova-pro"&gt;Steelseries Arctis Nova Pro&lt;/a&gt; headphones. They are amazing for what I need—they work great over 2.4 GHz, so I don&amp;rsquo;t experience noticeable latency like with Bluetooth, and I can connect four devices to the base station simultaneously. This is something I do daily when working on multiple computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never had any issues until I connected them to a Mac mini with an M2 processor. After an indeterminate amount of time, static noise started coming out of the headphones, getting progressively louder until they became unusable. Rebooting the headphones didn’t help, nor did changing the output device to something else and back again. If I hadn&amp;rsquo;t used them successfully on other devices, I would have assumed they were broken.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>