<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Technical on The Tymscar Blog</title><link>https://blog.tymscar.com/tags/technical/</link><description>Recent content in Technical on The Tymscar Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 23:20:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.tymscar.com/tags/technical/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Playing around with Gaussian Splat</title><link>https://blog.tymscar.com/posts/gaussiansplat/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 23:20:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.tymscar.com/posts/gaussiansplat/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Photogrammetry has held my interest for a very long time. After all, &lt;a href="https://www.tymscar.com/assets/images/visualisations/ezgif.com-gif-maker285292.gif"&gt;my profile picture&lt;/a&gt;, almost everywhere, is a LiDAR scan of my head that I accomplished with the FaceID of an old iPhone about five years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I stumbled upon &lt;a href="https://repo-sam.inria.fr/fungraph/3d-gaussian-splatting/3d_gaussian_splatting_high.pdf"&gt;a new paper about something called Gaussian Splatting&lt;/a&gt;. This topic is fascinating because, instead of creating a 3D mesh, it more closely resembles a point cloud that is expanded and shaped in such a way that it looks highly realistic. One usecase that interests me in particular is bringing these in as VR backdrops.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How I deploy private GitHub projects to local self-hosted servers (CI/CD)</title><link>https://blog.tymscar.com/posts/privategithubcicd/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 18:04:45 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.tymscar.com/posts/privategithubcicd/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="how-i-deploy-private-github-projects-to-local-self-hosted-servers-cicd"&gt;How I deploy private GitHub projects to local self-hosted servers (CI/CD)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a lot of experience with massive CI/CD pipelines that deploy private code to public servers. I&amp;rsquo;ve also worked with pipelines that deploy public repositories to private servers, such as my homelab. However, I never experimented with a pipeline that takes a private GitHub repo, builds it, and deploys it to a server on the LAN. That&amp;rsquo;s precisely what I needed for a project I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on that isn&amp;rsquo;t yet public.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Running Jetbrains remote dev servers on NixOS</title><link>https://blog.tymscar.com/posts/jetbrainsremotedevservernixos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:33:45 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.tymscar.com/posts/jetbrainsremotedevservernixos/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://blog.tymscar.com/jb-nix-remote-server/project.png" alt="A remote project"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EDIT: I have raised &lt;a href="https://github.com/NixOS/nixpkgs/pull/243533"&gt;a PR to fix this&lt;/a&gt; upstream and got it merged, so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to follow the guide anymore, you can just use the package on nixpkgs unstable for the time being and later on in the future, a stable branch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past year or so I have been very interested in &lt;a href="https://nixos.org/"&gt;NixOS and Nix&lt;/a&gt; in general.
I have set it up as my &lt;a href="https://github.com/tymscar/dotfiles"&gt;main OS on my desktop&lt;/a&gt;, I have used it on remote VPS instances, and I have used it for local projects as well in the shape of nix environments.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Hack The Midlands CTF 2021</title><link>https://blog.tymscar.com/posts/hackthemidlandsctf2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 18:12:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.tymscar.com/posts/hackthemidlandsctf2021/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://hackthemidlands.com/"&gt;HackTheMidlands&lt;/a&gt; is a 24-hour hackathon, or “creative marathon”, which was founded in 2016.
I used to participate back in the day, and I&amp;rsquo;ve even won a prize before, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mvLXkCgsXik"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; you can find a video about it! 📷&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="ctfs"&gt;CTFs🏁:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a programmer at heart I&amp;rsquo;ve never played seriously with &lt;a href="https://www.hackthebox.com/blog/what-is-ctf"&gt;capture the flag&lt;/a&gt; challenges before, but because I am busy with work I did not have the time and energy to participate in the coding part of the hackathon, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;ll give the CTF a try! It was a lot of fun for someone starting out with CTFs but with a good grasp of &lt;code&gt;*nix&lt;/code&gt; systems, programming, and web development!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>